ADARSH SHARMA

Front-End Developer

Visit Portfolio

A Bhavnagar, Gujarat

Github

in LinkedIn



+91-90444-77693

≥ ada70351@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a driven professional with 1.5+ years of experience, eager to learn and apply new skills in a dynamic environment. I excel in troubleshooting, problem-solving, and communication, complemented by strong leadership and technical expertise. I am seeking a challenging role where I can contribute to organizational success while further enhancing my capabilities.

EDUCATION

United College of Engineering and Research. (A.K.T.U., Lucknow, U.P.)

B.Tech. in Information Technology (2019 – 2023) CGPA: 6.6

Lucknow Public School, Lucknow, U.P.

Senior Secondary Education (2018) (CBSE) Percentage: 51%

Bhavan's K.D.K.V.M., Renukoot, U.P.

High School (2016) (CBSE) CGPA: 8.2

SKILLS

- HTML
- SASS
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- TYPO3 Fluid
- React Is
- GIT (CI/CD, Version Control)
- SQL
- UI/UX
- Vs Code Extension
- SEO, Accessibility
- C, Php Java, Python
- FileZilla Deployment
- · Node and Yarn
- SDLC & STLC
- Figma, XD, Sketch

CERTIFICATIONS

- Java | Internshala
- SQL | Great Learning
- Python | LinkedIn Learning
- Web Development | Coursera
- Azure Cloud Service | Microsoft Future Ready Talent

STRENGTH

HOBBIES

- · Team Work
- Leadership
- Solution Oriented Mindset
- порыцо
- Reading & WritingTravelling
- Games (Indoor/Outdoor)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer

Nitsan Technologies, Bhavnagar, Gujarat | Nov 2023 - Present

- Developed responsive web applications using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript to enhance functionality and user experience.
- Interacted with clients over calls to understand project requirements, address concerns, and provide updates on project status, ensuring alignment with client expectations and timelines.
- Prepared Technical Standard Reports, Speed Performance Reports, and maintained Client Hour Estimation Reports.
- Managed client communications, keeping them informed of progress and any changes, and maintained a high level of satisfaction.
- Collaborated with design and backend teams to deliver visually appealing and functional websites.
- Performed web analysis to monitor user behavior, track key performance metrics, and recommend improvements for better user experience.
- Maintained and updated existing websites by troubleshooting and debugging code, ensuring seamless operation across multiple browsers and devices.
- Implemented UI/UX best practices and conducted user testing to optimize website performance and drive engagement.
- Improved SEO by maintaining clean code, implementing meta tags, alt attributes, and other best practices to enhance search engine visibility.
- Ensured website accessibility by adhering to WCAG standards, using semantic HTML, ARIA roles, and keyboard navigation.
- Developed VS Code Extension: Typo3 Content Block Snippets

Technical Executive

Webtel Electrosoft Pvt. Ltd, New Delhi | June 2023 - Sept 2023

- Provided proactive technical support to end users via phone, email, and remote
 desktop tools, resolving over approx. 120 tickets per week with a 99% customer
 satisfaction rate.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to troubleshoot and address complex technical issues, resulting in a 20% decrease in overall service downtime.
- Implemented and maintained IT infrastructure upgrades, including software installations and network configurations, resulting in improved system performance and efficiency.
- Achievement: Rising Star of the month.

Project's

- T3Planet
- Century Casinos
- Quivo
- Helfen Hilft
- Ribe
- CSI Online
- Block Menue
- BergHotel
- Epoche Napoleon
- Body Performance
- BAVC Automobilclub

- Hithium
- Hohenlohe
- <u>NITSAN</u>
- Stadt Wolgast
- Stadt Weikersheim
- Multipurpose Templates
 - o T3Karma
 - T3Avatar
 - o T3Guru
 - T3 NGO
 - T3 React Bootstrap